Nikolas Rieble

Data Scientist

a: Lützowstraße 20, 81245 Munich

e: nikolas-rieble@protonmail.com

t: +49 172 1811 209

g: github.com/nikolasrieble



Profile

Engineer with 4 years of experience in applied data science. Implemented machine learning algorithms in Python for computer vision and time series analysis. Skilled at communication and training in statistics and mathematics. Persuasive and committed to empowering colleagues and customers with human-centered digitalization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Smart Factory Developer

since 2018

Hilti GmbH Industriegesellschaft für Befestigungstechnik

- Smart Factory architecture: Design of a modular system from data acquisition to reporting
- Project Management: evaluation and implementation of Industry 4.0 use cases

Student Researcher

2017 - 2018

Machine Learning/Intelligent Data Analysis Group, TUB

o Brain Computer Interface: Implementation of EEG data analysis in Matlab

Student Researcher

2016 - 2017

Department of Production Systems, Fraunhofer IPK

o Condition Monitoring: Classification of multidimensional time-series from production systems

Student Researcher

2015 - 2016

Department of Machine Tools and Factory Management, TUB

• Real-Time Stream Monitoring: Implementation and evaluation of pattern recognition algorithms

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Computational Engineering Science Technical University of Berlin B.Sc. Psychology University of Vienna B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering Technical University Stuttgart

PROJECTS

- Computer Vision: Random Ferns for Object Recognition in PolSAR radar images (Python)
- Operations Research: Processing Radioactive Waste in the US A mathematical model (GAMS)
- Robotics: Reconstruction of a robots environment using the Kinect Camera (ROS, Python)

Computer Literacy

- Programming: Python (including: numpy, pandas, scipy, sklearn), C#, Matlab, SQL, GAMS
- Dev Tools: Git, Bamboo, Jira
- Frameworks: ROS, Apache Spark